A Finding Aid to the Philip Evergood Papers, 1890-1971, in the Archives of American Art AAA.everphil
Archives of American Art
- Scrapbooks, 1924-1954; Series 7; 0.6 Linear feet Boxes 11-12
  Materials are arranged in chronological order.
  - Scrapbook #1, 1924-1935 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook #2, 1935-1937 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook #3, 1937-1939 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook #4, 1939-1954 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Artwork, 1905-1970; Series 8; 1.4 Linear feet Box 9, OV 14-20, RD 23
  Artwork consists of mixed media, including oils and watercolors, as well as graphite and pen and ink studies for future paintings. There are also sketches of nudes, animals, landscapes, buildings, and early examples of childhood drawings.
  - Childhood Sketches, Crayon, circa 1905-1910 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Oversized material housed in OV 14.
  - Childhood Sketches, Graphite, circa 1905-1915 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Childhood Sketches, Mixed Media, circa 1905-1915 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Childhood Sketches, Mounted, circa 1900-1915 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Sketches, Animals and Plants, circa 1940-1970 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Oversized material housed in OV 15.
  - Sketches, Artwork Ideas, circa 1940-1970 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    Oversized material housed in RD 23.
  - Sketches, Landscapes and Buildings, circa 1940-1970 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Sketches, Nudes, circa 1940-1970 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    Oversized material housed in OV 16-17.
  - Sketches, People, circa 1940-1970 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    Oversized material housed in OV 18.
  - Sketches, Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1970 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Studies, Mixed Media, Oil, and Watercolors, circa 1940-1970 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    Oversized material housed in OV 19-20.
  - Artwork by Others, circa 1905-1915 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Oversized Childhood Sketches from Box 9, Folders 8 and 11, circa 1905-1915 (Box OV 14)
  - Oversized Animals, Landscapes, and Buildings (sketches) from Box 9, Folders 12 and 14, circa 1940-1970 (Box OV 15)
  - Oversized Nudes (sketches) from Box 9, Folder 15, circa 1940-1970 (Box OV 16-17)
  - Oversized People (sketches) from Box 9, Folder 16, circa 1940-1970 (Box OV 18)
  - Oversized Mixed Media, Oils, and Watercolors from Box 9, Folder 18, circa 1940-1970 (Box OV 19-20)
  - Oversized Artwork Idea (sketch) from Box 9, Folder 13, circa 1940-1970 (Box RD 23)
- Photographic Materials, 1890-1970; Series 9; 1.1 Linear feet Box 9-10, OV 21-22
  Photographs are of Evergood; his parents and his wife Julia; exhibition galleries, events, and openings; and friends, including Elizabeth McCausland, Art Young, William Zoarch, Jack Levine, and Raphael Soyer. Among the photographers are Berenice Abbott, Arnold Newman, Guy Gillette, and Soichi Sunami. Photographs and negatives of artwork are primarily of oil paintings.
  - Evergood Family and Friends, circa 1890-1970 (Box 9, Folder 20-21)
    Oversized material housed in OV 21.
  - Evergood, Philip, Childhood, circa 1901-1920 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Evergood, Philip, circa 1920-1970 (Box 9, Folder 23-24)
    Oversized material housed in OV 22.
  - Exhibition Galleries, circa 1943-1950 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Exhibition Openings and Events, circa 1930-1970 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Photographs of Artwork, A-L, circa 1940-1970 (Box 9, Folder 27-31)
  - Photographs of Artwork, M-Z, circa 1940-1970 (Box 9, Folder 32-35)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Framed, circa 1940-1970 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Murals, circa 1940-1970 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Untitled, circa 1940-1970 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of Artwork, By Others, circa 1940-1960 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Negatives of Evergood and Artwork, circa 1950-1965 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Photographs of Evergood Family and Friends from Box 9, Folders 20-21, circa 1890-1970 (Box OV 21)
  - Oversized Photographs of Evergood, Philip (childhood) from Box 9, Folder 22, circa 1901-1920 (Box OV 21)
  - Oversized Photographs of Evergood, Philip from Box 9, Folders 23-24, circa 1920-1970 (Box OV 22)
  - Oversized Photographs of Artwork (untitled) from Box 10, Folder 3, circa 1940-1970 (Box OV 21)